--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:射手网  调校:小五  招募Q号:76846146
中世纪的时候 兴起了一种比赛
不管贵族或平民 都为之狂热
即使只有贵族骑士 可以参赛
那就是马上枪术比赛
对某个骑士而言 一个过气的前任冠军
这代表了结束
但对他的平民随从 威廉来说
这只是开始
我们该帮他吗？
Should we help him?
他得在两分钟内上场 不然就等于弃权
He's due in the lists in two minutes. Two minutes or forfeit.
这借我们
Lend us those.
右边 左边
Right. Left.
- 死了  - 什么？
- Dead.  - Eh?
两回合下来的比数是三比零
Three scores to none after two lances.
只要艾克特爵爷不摔马 我们就赢了
As long as Sir Ector doesn't fall off his horse,we've won.
他死了
He's dead.
- 什么意思？  - 他死了
What do you mean?  - His life's spark is covered in shite.
他的精神已远走 但臭味还在
His spirit is gone but his stench remains.
- 这样回答你的问题了吗？  - 不
- Does that answer your question?  - No,no,no.
不 他只是睡着了 叫醒他
No,he sleeps. Rouse him.
我三天没吃东西了！
I haven't eaten in three days!
我们也没吃啊！
None of us have!
- 我们得去找个神父来  - 不 他没死！
- Let's fetch a priest.  - No,he's not dead!
醒醒！ 快点！
You waKe up! Come on!
快啊！
Come on!
你这臭笨蛋！
You manKy git!
洛伦
Roland.
随从 艾克特爵爷必须马上报到 不然就等于弃权
Squire,Sir Ector must report at once or forfeit the match.
他马上过去
He's on his way.
我三天没吃东西了！
I haven't eaten in three days!
三天哪！ 你吃了什么 同伴？
Three days! What did you eat,mate?!
如果你没死 我就杀了你！
If you wasn't dead,I would Kill you!
我替他上场
I'll ride in his place.
脱掉他的盔甲 我替他上场
Strip his armor. I'm riding in his place.
华特 别踢他了！ 我替他上场 来帮我
Wat,stop KicKing him! I'm riding in his place. Help me.
威廉 你有什么头衔？
What's your name,William?
威廉柴契尔 把头衔告诉我啊
William Thatcher,answer me with your name.
不是威廉爵士
It's not Sir William.
也不是伯爵、公爵或威廉国王
It's not Count or DuKe or King William.
这我知道
I Know that.
要有贵族血统才能参赛
You must be of noble birth to compete.
那不重要 重要的是有饭吃 你到底想不想吃饭？
A detail. The landscape is food. Do you want to eat or not?
要是被贵族发现 我们就吃不完兜着走
If the nobles find out,there'll be the devil to pay.
那就祈祷他们不会发现
Then pray that they don't.
骑士传说
A.Knight`s.Tale.
面甲拉下
Visor.
快点 我们迟了
Come on,we're late.
目前比数是三比零 艾克特爵士领先
The score stands at three lances to none in favor of Sir Ector.
阿拉贡的菲力浦勋爵
Lord Philip of Aragon.
您准备好了吗？
Stand ye ready?
艾克特爵士 您准备好了吗？
Sir Ector. Stand ye ready?
准备好了吗？
Ready?
我跟艾克特爵士对打过很多次
I tilted against Sir Ector many times.
当他的练习靶 你从来没击中他
In practice as his target. You never strucK him.
- 别拿这些细节来烦我  - 为了食物 千万别摔下马
- Badger me not with details.  - The landscape. Stay on the horse.
他需要三分 他必须把你打下马
He needs 3 points. He has to KnocK you off the horse.
洛伦 我知道怎么记分
I Know how to score,Roland.
我这辈子等的就是这一刻
I've waited my whole life for this moment.
等艾克特爵爷死翘翘？
For Sir Ector to shite himself to death?
插进托架 托架
Get it in the cradle. In the cradle.
插进托架啊！
Get it in the cradle!
威廉 你还活着吗？
William,are you alive?
- 我们赢了！  - 你听得到我说话吗？
- We won! We won! - Can you hear me?
走开啦！ 威廉 你听得到吗？
Get off me! William,can you hear me?
我们赢了！
We won!
他在呼吸 他还有气！
He's breathing. He's breathing!
艾克特爵士
Sir Ector.
艾克特爵士 取下头盔
Sir Ector. Remove your helmet.
大人 最后一击 让我的头盔变形拿不下来了
My lord,the final blow of the lance has bent it onto my head.
他说最后一击
He says the final blow of the
大人 这位就是优胜者
I present your champion,my lord.
二十
Twenty.
不 十
No,10.
- 十五  - 好
- Fifteen.  - Done.
很好 再见了
Very good. Cheers.
十五个银币 他不要那个
Fifteen silver florins. He didn't want that.
五个给威廉
That's five for William.
五个给华特 另外五个 给要回英格兰老家的洛伦
Five for Wat. Five for Roland,who's going home to England.
我要直接去酒馆 鳗鱼派、乳酪饼
Straight to the pub for me. Eel pie,brie tart
薄荷夹心的艾菊蛋糕
tansy caKes with peppermint cream.
我们办得到
We could do this.
我们已经办到了 在你手上的可是银币啊
We've done it,boy. That's silver in your hand.
我是说我们可以靠比赛吃饭 我们可以打遍天下
No,I mean,we can do this. We can be champions.
把银币给我
Give us your coins.
快把银币给我
Give me your coins.
好 一个给你
Now,that's one for you.
一个给你
And onefor you.
这样就剩下十三个
Which leaves 13.
当作训练和治装的费用
That's 1 3 for training and outfitting.
再一个月就是鲁昂枪术比赛
The tournament in Rouen is in a month.
我们可以共享更大的奖
We could split a bigger prize.
再一个月我们就可以名利双收
In one month we'd be on our way to glory and riches.
或跟艾克特爵士一样去见阎王 威廉 我只想回家
Or lying in a ditch with Sir Ector. William,I just want to go home.
艾菊蛋糕和时萝小牛肉丸 我的五个银币给我
Tansy caKes. Dilled veal balls. I'll taKe my five now.
等等
Oh,wait up.
你走错路了！
You're going the wrong way!
你根本不会马上枪术比赛
You can't even joust.
只要够胆准备被痛击就行了 我胆子够大
Most of it is the guts to taKe a blow. Guts I have.
至于技巧呢？ 我有一个月的时间可以学
And technique? I have a month to learn that.
告诉我谁比我还会使剑
And name a man better with a sword than I am.
- 那是在练习的时候  - 你没有贵族血统
- In the practice ring.  - You're not of noble birth.
那就骗他们啊
So,we lie.
贵族一开始 是怎么成为贵族的？
How did the nobles become noble in the first place?
他们在剑尖下受勋 我就用长枪来受勋
They tooK it at the tip of a sword. I'll do it with a lance.
- 一支钝枪  - 华特 那无所谓
- A blunted lance.  - No matter,Wat.
命运可以改变 我才不要一辈子默默无闻
A man can change his stars. I won't spend the rest of my life as nothing.
那才叫没没无闻 那就是想要名利双收的下场
That is nothing. And that's where glory will taKe us.
我们只是平民 名利不是我们能享受的
We're peasants. Glory and riches are beyond our grasp.
但是把肚子喂饱？ 这种梦才可能实现
But a full stomach? That dream can come true.
如果你们能拿走银币 就去英格兰吃蛋糕吧
If you can taKe your coins,go eat caKe in England.
如果不能 就跟我走
But if you can't,you come with me.
瞧吧 钱并不重要
You see? Money doesn't matter.
看到我有多饿了吗？
See how hungry I am?!
- 看到了吗？  - 华特 去你的肚子
- Do you?!  - Damn your stomach,Wat!
洛伦 拜托你
Roland,please.
利用十三个银币 三个男人可以改变他们的命运
With 13 silver pieces,three men can change their stars.
威廉 上帝爱你
God love you,William.
我知道 我是爹不疼娘不爱
I Know,I Know. No one else will.
运气不好
UnlucKy.
- 他好像愈来愈糟了  - 他是愈来愈糟
- I thinK he's getting worse.  - He is getting worse.
换手
Switch.
名利双收 名利双收！
Glory and riches. Glory and riches!
你知道多危险了吧？
You see how dangerous it is?
快一点！ 快一点！ 好好发挥你的脚力！
Faster! Faster! All right,use those legs!
快啊 洛伦！ 再快点！
Come on,Roland. Faster! Faster!
你没击中
You missed it.
你已经练习几十遍了
You've done it dozens of times.
我想那表示我们应该再来一次
Well,I guess that means we should do it again.
来吧
Come on.
快啊 小马儿
Come on,ponies.
给他好看
Fong him.
快一点 保持平衡
Faster. Balance.
不 慢一点 稳一点
No,slower. Keep it steady.
我穿过去了！ 瞧 我穿过去了！
I got it! Look,I got it!
就快了
Any minute now.
- 比较好了  - 不错
- Yes,better.  - Nice.
- 换我骑了  - 不
- It's my turn to ride.  - No.
我们还没到指定的地方 而且你不该骑
We haven't reached the marKer. And you shouldn't.
我的随从骑马 我却走路 这样能看吗？
How would it looK if my squire rode while I walKed?
我才不管！ 该我骑了！ 该我骑了！
I don't give a witch's teat! It's my turn! It's my turn!
也许大家都不该骑 这匹马体力不比从前了
Maybe nobody should ride. The horse is not what he used to be.
好吧
Fine. Fine.
早
Morning.
先生
Hoy,sir.
您在做什么？
What are you doing?
呃 跋涉
Uhtrudging.
你知道跋涉吧？ 跋涉啊？
You Know,trudging? To trudge?
缓慢、疲惫、沮丧
To trudge the slow,weary
却意志坚定地走着 我什么都不剩
depressing,yet determined walK of a man who had nothing left
只剩下继续向前迈进的冲动
except the impulse to simply soldier on.
你被抢了吗？
Were you robbed?
有意思的问题 是的
Interesting question. Yes.
同时呢 我也要大声地说¨不是〃
And at the same time,a huge,resounding,"No."
其实 这比较像是 非自愿性的贫穷
It's more a sort of involuntary vow of poverty,really.
但往好的一面看 跋涉代表着自豪
But on the brighter side,trudging does represent pride.
自豪、果断 全心相信全知全能的上帝
Pride,resolve and faith in the good Lord Almighty.
基督啊 求求您 拯救我免于苦
Please,Christ,rescue me from my tribu-
难
lations.
你是谁？
Who are you?
荆棘里的百合
Lilium inter spinas.
The lily among the thorns.
姓乔瑟名杰佛瑞 以写作为业
Geoffrey Chaucer's the name. Writing's the game.
乔瑟？
Chaucer?
杰佛瑞乔瑟 作家啊？
Geoffrey Chaucer,the writer?
- 作什么？  - “作什么？” 作家
- A what?  - "A what?" A writer.
我以墨水在羊皮纸上书写 给我一文钱 我什么都帮你写
I write with inK and parchment. For a penny,I'll scribble anything.
召集令、法令、诏书 授权书、贵族血统证明
Summonses,decrees,edicts,warrants,patents of nobility.
我还以写诗闻名 如果有灵感的话
I've been Known to jot down a poem,if the muse descends.
你们大概看过我的书 公爵夫人之书
You probably read my booK,The Book of the Duchess.
那是个寓言
Well,it was allegorical.
我们不会因此对你有成见的 每个人都有权自作决定
We won't hold it against you. Each man decides that for himself.
你刚说贵族血统证明吗？
Did you say patents of nobility?
没错 我是这么说的
That's right. I did.
你们三位是？
And you gentlemen are?
我是乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士 来自盖德兰
I am Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
他们是我忠心的随从 道京顿的戴夫
These are my faithful squires,Delves of Dodgington
还有克鲁伊的佛赫斯特
and Fowlehurst of Crewe.
我是狮心理察 幸会
I'm Richard the Lionheart. A pleasure.
不 我是查理大帝！ 施洗者约翰！
No,I'm Charlemagne! John the Baptist!
好了！
All right!
闭嘴 否则我让你开不了口
Hold your tongue,sir,or lose it.
说真的 我相信你
Now you see that,I do believe
乌瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
谢谢你
ThanK you
杰夫
Geoff.
赤裸大师 你还有话要说 或者我们可以上路了？
Have you any more to say,Master Nude,or may we be on our way?
- 去枪术比赛？  - 这条是到鲁昂的路
- Off to the tournament?  - This is the road to Rouen.
那还不一定呢 鲁昂那里限制得很严
That remains to be seen. They're limiting the field at Rouen.
父母双方四代都是贵族 才会被认定是贵族
Noble birth must be established for four generations on either side.
还要附贵族血统证明书
Patents of nobility must be provided.
听着 只要给我衣服
Listen,clothe me
给我鞋子 喂饱我 你的证明书就不成问题
shoe me,for God's saKe,feed me and you'll have your patents.
不
No.
- 贵族血统证明书  - 我们需要他
- Patents of nobility.  - We need him. We need him.
- 我来处理  - 好声好气点
- Let me handle it.  - Be nice.
好声好气 好声好气
Nice,nice,nice.
好
All right.
你要是敢背叛我们 我就打得你吐破肠流
Betray us and I will fong you until your insides are out
面目全非 内脏变外脏
your outsides are in and your entrails are your extrails.
我会让你痛苦
Pain.
非常痛苦
Lots of pain.
比赛大会会场 鲁昂
为您介绍乌瑞克爵士 其外祖父为席拉德冯瑞克堡
I present Sir Ulrich,whose mother's father was Shilhard von Rechberg
曾祖为萨克森的顾尔夫公爵 曾曾祖纪林 曾曾曾祖温狄胥
son of the DuKe Guelph of Saxony,son of Ghibellines,son of Wendish.
- 而温狄胥继承了  - 可以了 传令人
- Wendish inherited the fief  - That'll do,herald.
六代很够了 证明书给我看
Six generations is more than enough. Show me the patents.
指出你的乌瑞克大人 要参加哪几场比赛
Indicate in which events shall your Lord Ulrich compete.
他第一场出战的是摩提莫大人
He'll first meet Roger Lord Mortimer.
非常谢谢你
ThanK you very much.
真不敢相信 乔瑟 你做到了
I can't believe it. You did it,Chaucer.
我得谢谢你 我本来不认为 我们会有机会
I thanK you. I didn't thinK we had a chance.
威廉 我很乐意帮忙
My pleasure,William.
你不介意的话 我想留下来
If you don't mind,I'll sticK around.
当我的传令人吧 我赢的话你也有份
Be my herald,you'll get part of the winnings.
说定了 现在请容我离开 我必须去找一个人谈生意
Done. Now if you don't mind,I have to see a man about a dog.
离开了奇普塞
Walking out from Cheapside
寻找大好前程
My fortunes for to seek
我走过泰晤士河畔
I passed along the River Thames
河水臭气冲天
Its Waters did they reek
我在那儿遇见一位美丽姑娘
"Was there I met a pretty lass
她说她名叫妮尔
She said her name Was Nell
不管天堂地狱 我都跟她去
Bell or hell rhymes with Nell.
你愿意跟我说话吗？
Would you speaK to me?
说话啊
Ah,to speaK.
先生 女人不该多话的
Sir,my sex are marKed by their silence.
我很想听你说话 即使我会因此失去双耳
I would hear you speaK if it cost me my ears.
很好 因为我可不希望 一生沉默无语
That is well,for I do not want silence in my life.
告诉我你叫什么名字
Tell me your name.
- 若我很丑 你还会在乎吗？  - 会
- Would you care if I were ugly?  - Yes
我是说不会 我是说
I mean,no. I mean
你亵渎了上帝的居所！
You desecrate the house of God!
告诉我你的名字
Tell me your name.
你要拿我的名字做什么呢 猎人先生？
And what would you do with my name,Sir Hunter?
叫我狐狸吧 我对你而言不过如此
Call me a fox,for that is all I am to you.
性感美女 那我就先叫你狐狸 直到我问出你的名字
Then a fox you shall be until I find your name,my foxy lady.
我承认他这猎人挺英俊的
He's a handsome hunter. I give him that.
小姐们 你们不震惊吗？
Does this not shocK you,ladies?
当然震惊啊 大人
Certainly,my lord.
我笑是因为怕自己哭出来
I only laugh just to Keep from weeping.
美貌真是诅咒啊
Beauty is such a curse.
祈祷你年华早逝
Pray your years come swiftly.
花容尽褪 好更尽心服侍上帝
Pray your beauty fades so you may better serve God.
我有啊 我常常这么祈祷
Oh,I do,my lord. I pray for it all the time.
上帝啊 你为何诅咒我 给我这张脸？
Why,God,did you curse me with this face?
上帝自有他的道理 但我们可能无从得知
God's will has a purpose,but we may not Know it.
这真好看
Well,that is lovely.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein
打败摩提莫大人 比数是一比零
defeats Roger Lord Mortimer one lance to none.
真简单 他们会以为 我从来没打赢过
Easy. They'll thinK l never broKe a lance before.
- 你是没打赢过啊！  - 乌瑞克赢过数千次
- But you haven't!  - Ulrich's broKen thousands of lances.
走吧 该去比剑了
Come on. You're due in the sword ring.
我的盔甲松了
My armor's loose.
可恶 我会挡不住上方的攻击
Shite. I can't blocK an overhead.
现在来不及修了 我们比剑已经迟到了
We can't fix it now. We're overdue in the sword ring.
不该比两种的 太赶了
It was a mistaKe to do two events. I'm too hurried.
- 我退出比剑好了  - 剑术是你最拿手的
- I'll withdraw from the sword.  - Sword's what you're best at.
但是比长枪的奖赏比较丰富 名声也比较响亮
But the prizes and prestige are bigger in the joust.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦？ 我是传唤者赛门
Ulrich von Lichtenstein? I am Simon the Summoner.
而我比剑快迟到了
I'm overdue at the sword ring.
我谨代表你的传令人留下你
I must detain you on behalf of your herald.
你才没有被抢
You Were never robbed.
我有酗赌的问题
I have a gambling problem.
我控制不了自己
I can't help myself.
而这些人真的会
And these people will
剥光你的衣服
Iiterally taKe the clothes off your bacK.
你要我们怎么办？
What are we supposed to do?
他跟我们保证他的主人 也就是你 会付我们钱
He assured us that you,his liege,would pay us.
你是什么人来着？
And who are you?
彼得 卑微的免罪符小贩
Peter,a humble pardoner
和宗教遗物供应商
and purveyor of religious relics.
他欠了多少钱？
How much does he owe?
十个金币
Ten gold florins.
你这蠢蛋
You manKy git!
- 痛吧 痛死好了  - 快把他拉开
- Pain! Pain! TaKe the pain!  - Get him off me!
华特 放开他
Wat,let him go!
如果我不付钱 你会对他怎样？
What would you do to him if I was to refuse?
我们会谨代表上帝
We,on behalf of the Lord God
要他用命来还 好让他了解
will taKe it from his flesh so that he may understand
赌博是有罪的
that gambling is a sin.
别这样
Oh,come on.
威廉 求求你
Please,Will.
求你帮我好吗 乌瑞克爵士？
Please,will you help me,Sir Ulrich?
我保证你不会后悔的
I promise you won't regret it.
我没那么多钱
I don't have the money.
放了他
Release him
把衣服还他吧
and give him bacK his clothes.
你们会拿到钱的
And you'll get it.
没问题
Done.
你说谎
You lied.
对 我说谎 我是作家 我对真话的定义很广泛
Yes,I lied. I'm a writer. I give the truth scope!
看哪 我的乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦大人
Behold my Lord Ulrich von Lichtenstein,son of
- 太迟了 他要出场了  - 好吧
- Too late. He's been announced.  - Fine.
先击中十下者为胜 先由乌瑞克爵士受击
Ten blows by sword. Sir Ulrich to receive first.
击中了
StriKe!
别再让他打中你了
Stop letting him hit you!
闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up! Shut up!
沃特罗令爵士得两分
Two striKes for Sir Walter Loring!
换乌瑞克爵士出剑！
Sir Ulrich to striKe!
- 该你了  - 加油！
- Now it's your turn!  - Come on!
击中了
StriKe!
那是我教他的！ 是我教他的！
I taught him that! That's me!
乌瑞克爵士以五比二获胜！
Sir Ulrich prevails,five striKes to two!
好耶！
Yes!
看哪 我的乌瑞克大人！ 他稳若磐石 耸立如泰山！
Behold my Lord Ulrich! The rocK! The hard place!
他像盖德兰来的一阵风 横扫而过！
LiKe a wind from Gelderland,he sweeps by!
从他的家乡吹袭过来 寻求胜利和荣耀！
Blown far from his homeland in search of glory and honor!
我们行走在他引发的骚动中！
We walK in the garden of his turbulence!
好耶！
Yeah!
- 你是冠军  - 剑术之冠
- You're champion.  - Of the sword.
我们不就是为此而来吗？ 走吧
Isn't that why we're here? Come on.
想碰碰他吗？ 你们想碰碰他吗？
Do you want to touch him? Do you want to touch him?
我们应该留点钱修盔甲的
We should've saved our money for the blacKsmith.
我现在没钱付你
I can't pay you noW
- 但我保证会付 只要  - 不行！ 钱
- but I promise I will,just as  - No! Money.
- 请问一下  - 拿钱来再说 光说没用
- Excuse me.  - Cash first,not promises.
离开吧
Go on.
先生 请问一下
Excuse me,sir.
去蹄铁匠那里试试吧
You might try the farris.
女的？
A woman?
大人 乞丐是没得选的
Beggars cannot be choosers,my lord.
谢谢
ThanK you.
- 请问一下  - 我不做白工
- Excuse me.  - I don't worK for free.
- 盔甲破损我无法比赛  - 那是你的问题 不是我的
- I can't joust with broKen armor.  - That's your problem,not mine.
我流的每一滴汗都有价钱
Each drop of this sweat has a price on it.
好吧 他们叫我 别傻到来问你
Just as well. They told me I was daft to even asK.
- 谁？  - 其他的盔甲匠
- Who? - The other armorers.
他们是不是说我修不好 因为我是女人？
Did they say I couldn't do it because I'm a woman?
他们说你擅长的是马蹄铁 不是盔甲
They said you're good with horseshoes,not armor.
没人提什么女人不女人的
No one mentioned you being a woman.
猫肉！ 热酒！
Cat's meat! Hot Wine!
小姐 我会为你 赢得这场锦标赛的
Lady,I will win this tournament for you.
不！ 是我会为你而赢
Nay! I will win for you.
容我介绍阿德玛伯爵
May I present Count Adhemar
法国长枪赛的优胜者 圣埃米里翁大赛的冠军
winner of the joust in France and champion at Saint- Emilion.
在基督教世界最美的女子面前 那一切都无足轻重了
All forgotten when standing before the most beautiful woman in Christendom.
伯爵 你只是装个样子 或是真的在打仗？
Do you only pretend to fight,Count Adhemar,or wage real war as well?
我是自由连队的领导人 我的军队在法国南部
I am leader of the free companies. My army is in southern France.
杰夫 那就是我仰慕的女人
Geoff,it's my lady.
- 威廉 你目标定太高了  - 我没有其他的目标了
- William,you aim too high.  - I don't Know any other way to aim.
- 专心  - 我该跟她说些什么？
- Concentrate.  - What should I say to her?
你对枪术比赛有何看法？
What do you thinK of the joust?
非常唐突
It's very abrupt.
规则我也不了解
And I don't understand the rules.
那就让我来教你
Then I shall educate you.
一场比赛分三回合
A match is three lances.
击中对手腰颈之间而断枪 得一分
One point is given for breaKing a lance between the waist and necK.
击落面甲而断枪 得两分 这很困难
Two points for breaKing on the helmet. It's difficult.
面甲会弹回来 所以多半只是一闪而过
The helmet sweeps bacK. Most blows glance off.
让对手落地得三分
Three points for bearing a rider to the ground.
而且 如果你让对手落地 他的马就是你的了
Also,if you bear a rider to the ground,you win his horse.
有人在枪术比赛中丧命吗？
Do men die in the joust?
长枪头是装上了冠状的钝器
Lance points are tipped with coronals,which blunts them.
当然 难免会有意外
Of course,accidents happen.
约瑟琳 而我本身从未落马过
I myself,Jocelyn,have never been unhorsed.
我也是
Nor have l.
小姐 您的大名
Your name,lady.
我还是需要知道
I still need to hear it.
猎人先生 你还真坚持
Sir Hunter,you persist.
或许天使没有名字 只有美丽的脸庞
Perhaps angels have no names. Only beautiful faces.
请问你是？
And you are?
我是 嗯
I am,um.
你忘了吗？
Have you forgotten?
或者你就叫“嗯”爵士
Or your name is Sir "Um."
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦 来自盖德兰
Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
我也会记不住 真难念啊
I'd forget as well. What a mouthful.
- 先生 您的盔甲  - 怎么样？
- Your armor,sir.  - What about it?
您真时髦 穿这么件古董 若您获胜 定会创造新风潮
How stylish of you to wear an antique. You'll start a new fashion if you win.
那样我祖父就能 再度穿他的旧衣外出了
My grandfather will be able to wear his in public again.
还有盾牌 多有趣啊
And a shield. How quaint.
有些穷乡僻壤的骑士 只比平民好一点点
Some of these poor country Knights,little better than peasants.
华勒斯
the second son
普西佛爵士 沃里克的第三伯爵的二公子
of Sir Wallace Percival,third Earl of WarwicK.
各位大人、小姐
My lords,my ladies
很荣幸向各位介绍 我的主人
it is with honor I introduce my liege
汤玛斯寇维尔爵士
Sir Thomas Colville.
你很行
You're good.
你非常行
You're very good.
各位大人
My lords
各位小姐
my ladies
以及其他 没有座位的诸位
and everybody else here not sitting on a cushion
今天
today
在场的各位是平等的
you find yourselves equals.
因为你们同样都受到神佑
For you are all equally blessed.
因为我很自豪
For I have the pride
很荣幸 不 是很高兴
the privilege,nay,the pleasure
位各位介绍一位 由骑士世家出身的骑士
of introducing to you a Knight sired by Knights.
他的血统可追溯至
A Knight who can trace his lineage bacK
查理曼大帝之前的时代
beyond Charlemagne.
我初次遇见他
I first met him
是在耶路撒冷附近的山顶
atop a mountain near Jerusalem
他向上帝祈祷
praying to God
请他原谅他剑上沾满了
asKing his forgiveness for the Saracen blood
撒拉逊人的血
spilt by his sword.
接着 在意大利 他更令我觉得不可思议
Next,he amazed me still further in Italy
当他拯救一位失怙的孤女
when he saved a fatherless beauty
免于她恶叔父的残害
from the would be ravishings of her dreadful uncle.
在希腊
In Greece
他保持缄默一年
he spent a year in silence
只为求更加了解
just to better understand the sound
轻声细语
of a whisper.
我就不再锦上添花 也不再多费唇舌
So without further gilding the lily and with no more ado
我要介绍给各位 安详平静的追寻者
I give to you the SeeKer of Serenity
意大利贞节的保护者
Protector of Italian Virginity
上帝旨意的执行者 独一无二的
the Enforcer of our Lord God,the one,the only
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士！
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein!
谢谢 谢谢各位！ 我整个星期都会在这里
ThanK you! ThanK you! I'll be here all weeK.
真与众不同啊
That was different.
是我们颂扬每个人 独特之处的时候了
It's time we celebrated our differences.
只要不在公开场合
Just maybe not in public.
你
You.
是的 我很清楚 我很快就会被好好修理了
Yes,I'm well aware a good fonging is on the way.
对 没错
Oh,yeah. Oh,yeah.
我负责引他们注意 你去赢得他们的心
I got their attention. You win their hearts.
非常好
Very good.
- 杰夫 她刚刚有看吗？  - 什么？
Was she watching? Geoff. What?
- 她看了我吗？  - 是的
- Did she see me?  - Yes,she did.
- 她看到我受击？  - 是的
- Did she see me taKe the hit?  - Yes.
- 她担心吗？  - 她眼泪盈眶 太糟了
- Was she concerned?  - Her eyes welled up. Just awful.
寇维尔技巧很完美 我以前从未见过他
Colville has perfect technique. I've never seen him before.
我也是
Nor I.
但这个利顿斯坦
But this Lichtenstein.
他的技巧只在入门阶段 风格更是完全不存在
His technique,rudimentary. Style,nonexistent.
然而 他无所畏惧
Still,he's fearless.
无所畏惧？ 怎么说？
Fearless? How so?
面甲里的缝隙很窄 但碎木片可以穿透其间
The slit in the visor is narrow,but splinters can penetrate it.
大多数骑士在最后一瞬间 都会抬起下巴
Most Knights raise their chins at the last instant.
虽看不到对手 却能保护双眼 乌瑞克则否
You lose sight of your opponent,but protect your eyes. Ulrich doesn't.
他眼睛牢牢盯着目标
He Keeps his eye on the target.
不折不扣的猎人
A true hunter.
乌瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich
我要退出了
I'm through.
但我以前从未中途退出
But I've never not finished before.
我希望完整保持我的荣誉
I wish to Keep my honor intact.
不分胜负 寇维尔受伤了
A draw. And Colville is hurt.
寇维尔退出 乌瑞克晋级
Colville withdraws. Ulrich advances.
乌瑞克为何不乘胜追击？
Why didn't Ulrich finish him?
他慈悲为怀
He shows mercy.
那么他就展露了弱点 慈悲只会使人脆弱
Then he shows his weaKness. That's all mercy is.
威廉 看在胜利的份上 快睡吧
For the love of victory,William,go to sleep.
我睡不着
I can't.
爱情给了我翅膀 我必须飞翔
Love has given me wings,so I must fly.
我无法解释
I can't explain it.
- 她让我自觉像个诗人 - 你或许自觉像诗人
- She maKes me feel liKe a poet.  - You may feel liKe a poet
但你听起来像个白痴
but you sound liKe an idiot.
- 你连她的名字都不知道  - 她的名字？
- You don't even Know her name.  - Her name?
她叫爱芙萝黛蒂
Her name is Aphrodite.
卡丽普索、维纳斯 随你选
Calypso. Venus. TaKe your picK.
女人让人意志软弱
Women weaKen the heart.
没有了意志 你就无法获胜
Without your heart,you cannot win.
- 但她的眼睛  - 专心
- But her eyes  - Concentrate.
艾菊蛋糕！
Tansy caKes!
阿德玛伯爵派人来传话
Count Adhemar sends Word.
他说他会为你赢得这场锦标赛
He said he will win this tournament for you.
他已赢过许多次 他是为他自己和他的荣誉而赢
He's won many. He wins them for himself and his own honor.
他这么说是毫无价值的
It's nothing to say he wins them for me.
他希望能再次跟您谈谈
He wishes to speaK to you again.
而不是听我说话
Not to hear a word I say.
阿德玛要他的女人保持沉默
Adhemar wants his women silent.
你会要乌瑞克爵士 为你赢得这场锦标赛吗？
Would you have Sir Ulrich win the tournament for you?
不
No.
他是唯一一个 未许诺要这么做的骑士
And he is the only Knight who has not promised to do so.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
我要他赢得我的心
I would have him win my heart.
阿德玛！ 阿德玛！ 阿德玛！
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
真帅啊
Oh,lovely.
我不认为我看过阿德玛伯爵输
I don't thinK I've ever seen Count Adhemar lose.
的确 但打败了他 你就会第一个看到
No,but defeat him and you'll see it firsthand.
我的主人
My liege
乌瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
这位是克丽丝堤亚娜
Christiana.
- 我家小姐吩咐你戴上这个  - 当然
- My lady bids you wear this toKen.  - Of course.
她还要我告诉你 她名叫
She also said to tell you,her name
约瑟琳
is Jocelyn.
- 再会  - 再会
- Au revoir.  - Au revoir.
约瑟琳
Oh,Jocelyn.
专心比赛
Concentrate.
我无法呼吸
I can't breathe.
毫无风格可言
No style whatsoever.
铁砧也是如此
But neither has an anvil.
- 他出手真是惊人地有力  - 但是不完美 瞄得太高了
- He hits like a hammer. Amazing.  - But not perfect. He aims high.
肩膀向后 他可能会往右边刺
Roll your shoulder back,his blow may go right.
但要是他往我左边刺 我就毁了
But if he strikes to my left,I'll be obliterated.
我没说这不是场赌博
I didn't say it wasn't a gamble.
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
威廉？
William?
威廉 这里
William,here.
过来这里
Come here.
总有一天我会成为骑士
Someday I'll be a knight.
补屋顶工匠家的孩子？ 骑士？
A thatcher's son? A knight?
你还不如试着改变命运呢
You might as well try to change the stars.
父亲 有可能吗？
Can it be done,Father?
- 人可以改变命运吗？  - 可以的 威廉
- Can a man change the stars?  - Yes,William.
如果一个人信心坚定 他可以成就任何事情
If he believes enough,a man can do anything.
来
Come here.
乌瑞克 再去锻炼锻炼吧
Gain more bearing,Ulrich.
等你够资格了再来见我
See me again when you're worthy.
我非要你好看不可！
I'll fong you in the arse!
大人 精采啊 真精采
Well done,my lord! Well done.
- 你这混帐  - 快去看看乌瑞克
- You bastard!  - Go and see to Ulrich.
去看看乌瑞克
Go see to Ulrich.
大人 漂亮
Well done,my lord.
赢得真高尚
A noble victory.
小姐 这应该是你的
My lady,I believe this is yours.
长矛的优胜者是
For long spear on foot
潘多佛马拉泰斯塔
Pandolfo Malatesta.
剑术的优胜者是 乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
For sword on foot,Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
最后 马上枪术以及锦标赛的 冠军是
Finally,for the mounted joust and tournament champion
安竺的阿德玛伯爵
Adhemar,Count of Anjou.
阿德玛！ 阿德玛！ 阿德玛！
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
这几位就是优胜者
I present to you your champions.
下一次 你会躺在地上 仰望着我
Next time,you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
拜托 你打也打了 比也比了
Please. You have been weighed,
大家都知道你能力不足
you have been measured
继续保持剑术方面的战绩
Keep winning the sword.
- 我不比剑了 - 那是你最擅长的啊
- I won't compete in it.  - It's your best.
不 除非得到总冠军 否则什么都不算数
No. It's tournament champion or nothing at all.
十个银币 这应该够了
Ten florins. That should do.
乔瑟 今晚还有得赌 觉得手气还顺吗？
Sixes and sevens tonight,Chaucer. Do you feel lucky?
- 你衣服穿得够多吗？  - 滚吧 我不想再看到你们
- Have you enough clothes?  - Be gone. I'm done with you.
除了展开我的报复
Except to exact my revenge.
你能对我们怎样？
What on earth could you possibly do to us?
我会在小说里把你们开膛剖腹
I will eviscerate you in fiction.
把你们的丑恶和缺点 钜细靡遗地描述出来
Every last pimple,every last character flaw.
我曾经赤裸着身体一天 我要你们永生都赤身露体
I was naked for a day. You will be naked for eternity.
我有预感我们会再见
I have a feeling we shall meet again.
蹄铁匠 这是我们欠你的
Here,farris,take what we owe you.
你身上穿的盔甲 不是为你订制的吧？
The armor you wear,it wasn't made for you,was it?
那又怎样？
So?
我可以做出让你 甚至感觉不到重量的盔甲
I could make armor you wouldn't even know you wore it.
那要多少钱？
What's the cost?
只要带我到巴黎就好
Just take me as far as Paris.
我们不需要伴 拿着你的金块走吧
We travel alone. Take your gold and go.
- 能拿的尽量拿 快打包吧  - 你干嘛这么急着走？
- Get what you can. Let's pack.  - Why are we leaving so soon?
离下一场大赛只剩一周 现在走 才能让马休息
The next tournament is in a week. We can walk now and save the horse.
你必须参加庆祝会 跳舞、跟大家认识
You must go to the banquet. You'll dance and make an appearance.
让阿德玛再次嘲笑我？ 不
Let Adhemar laugh at me again? No!
- 要  - 不！
- Yes!  - No!
我家小姐想知道 你家主人今晚外衣的颜色
My lady would know the color of your lord's tunic tonight.
- 他的外衣？  - 是的 她好穿相搭的颜色
- His tunic?  - Yes,so she can dress to match him.
我们很遗憾必须告诉你家小姐 他不会参加
We regret to inform your lady he won't be attending- -
- 传令的 你别代我回答  - 是的 大人
- Herald,do not give my answers!  - Yes,my lord.
随从 回答她
Squire,answer her.
我今晚的外衣是什么颜色？
What color is my tunic tonight?
绿色
Green.
滚边用
Trimmed in a kind of
淡淡的绿
pale green
配上
with
木质系扣
uh,wooden toggles.
我会转告我家小姐
I will tell my lady.
- 完蛋了  - 不 这样很好
- This is a disaster!  - No,it'll tunic up quite nicely.
洛伦 我不是说外衣
That's not a disaster,Roland.
我不会跳舞
I don't know how to dance.
一 二 三 四
And one and two and three and four.
手要轻一点 像停在枝头上的鸟儿
Your hand should be light,like a birdie on a branch.
一 二 三 四
And one,two and three and four.
华特不许带舞 他跳得像女孩子似的
And Wat doesn't lead,he follows like a girl.
一 二
And one and two and
旋转 旋转 旋转
twirly,twirly,twirly.
一 二 你还是没跳对
And one and two,and you're still getting it wrong.
一 二 三 四
And one and two and three and four.
你可以打我一整天 因为你的力道像什么？
You can hit me all day because you punch like a what?
女孩子
A girl.
- 够了！  - 回去！ 华特 安静！
- Enough!  - Get back! Wat,quiet!
- 是他开始的  - 你明知道他很暴躁！
- He starts it.  - You know he's touchy!
难道你可以教得更好？
Oh,and you can do better?
- 当然  - 那就让我们瞧瞧
- Of course.  - Then show us.
不
No.
我都这么尽心尽力了 你最好礼貌地拜托她
If I'm making all this effort,you'd best ask her nicely.
凯蒂 对不起
I'm sorry,Kate.
不知道你是否可以 教我们该怎么跳舞
I was wondering if you'd care to show us how to dance.
- 拜托你 - 拜托啦
- Please.  - Please.
一 二 三 四
And one and two,three and four.
五 六 七 换舞伴
Five,six,seven,change partners.
一 二 三 四
And one,two,three,four
五 六 七
five,six,seven.
波洛奈兹舞
Polonaise. And one.
你不会不整理头发就去吧？
Are you wearing your hair like that?
有其他的发型吗？
Is there another way?
乌瑞克爵士 你帅气极了
Sir Ulrich,you look fantastic.
约瑟琳 你看起来
Jocelyn,you look.
呃 你
Uh,you
让我联想到圣经
remind me of the Bible.
当上帝让太阳静止 好让约书亚打败亚摩利人
When God stopped the sun to give Joshua time to defeat the Amorites.
我不明白
I don't understand.
若我能求上帝一件事
If I could ask God one thing
那就是让月亮静止
it would be to stop the moon.
让月亮静止 让这个夜晚
Stop the moon and make this night
和你的美丽
and your beauty
持续到永远
Iast forever.
你要跳哪种舞？ 库朗特舞？
What dance will you have? A coranto?
或是低步舞？
Or a basse dance?
乌瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
你何不让我们看看 贵国的舞步？
Why don't you show us a dance of your country?
让我们看看盖德兰的舞步
Show us a dance of Gelderland.
是的 盖德兰
Yes. Gelderland.
那很像法兰多拉舞
Well,it's a lot like the farandole
但有些不同
but with some differences.
先鞠躬
Well,you bow.
然后
And
and.
各位请就定位
Places. Places.
怎么了？
What?
- 我不知道 太小太轻了  - 他会被打扁 打到死翘翘
- I don't know. Too small,too light.  - He'll be crushed. Killed.
不会 我发现炼钢的新方法 做起来比较薄 比较小
No. I found a new way to heat steel. It's thinner,smaller
但是一样坚固
but just as strong.
这是什么？
What are these?
我的商标 以备有其他骑士 喜欢我做的盔甲
The marks of my trade should another knight admire the armor.
活动活动 感受它的轻巧
Twist and bend. Feel the movement.
- 但我终究会被击中  - 然后死掉
- But eventually I will be struck.  - And then death.
你有勇气测试看看吗？
Do you at least have the courage to test it?
你还好吗？
You okay?
我什么感觉都没有
I didn't feel a thing.
枪术比赛会场 拉格尼叙马恩
- 那位骑士是谁？  - 皮耶寇特尼
- Who's that knight?  - Piers Courtenay.
他为了筹款参加枪术比赛 今年已经提高税收三次了
He's raised taxes on his land 3 times this year to pay for tournament.
他的人民在挨饿受苦 他却在大肆庆祝
His people starve while he sits at banquet.
很有可能是真的吧
It's probably true.
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
阿德玛伯爵
The Count Adhemar
菲利浦德维崔之子
son of Philippe de Vitry
吉尔之孙
son of Gilles
自由连队的领导者
master of the free companies
雄壮威武的卫冕者
defender of his enormous manhood
骑士精神的良好楷模
a shining example of chivalry
还有香槟
and champagne.
说得好！
Nice work!
精采极了！
Bravo!
仔细观察阿德玛的动作 找出他的弱点
Watch every move Adhemar makes. We'll find a weakness.
寇维尔看起来状况很好
Well,Colville looks fit.
我的主人
my liege
华特斯普西佛爵士二公子
the second son of Sir Wallace Percival.
我谨以最深的敬意
It is my deepest honor
以我最深的敬意向各位介绍
My deepest honor to present to you.
大人 是爱德华 他们很肯定
It's Edward,my lord. They're sure of it.
显赫的汤玛斯寇维尔爵士！
the illustrious Sir Thomas Colville!
阿德玛退出比赛了
Adhemar withdrew.
会那样退出只代表一件事
To withdraw like that means one thing.
皇室
Royalty.
我去打听看看
I'll see what I can find out.
准备降旗
Prepare to drop the flag.
不 还不要 等等 听着
No,no. Not yet. Wait,listen.
乐手们 快吹号
Musicians,announce.
- 我有事跟我主人报告  - 那就去吧
- I must speak with my lord.  - Then go.
看你能否快过基督复临
See if you can beat the Second Coming.
慢着！ 等等！
Wait! Wait!
寇维尔就是黑王子爱德华 英格兰的王储
Colville is Edward,the Black Prince,future king of England.
他跟我一样 为了参赛而掩饰身份
He's in disguise like me so he can compete.
他每战必胜 攻无不克
He's never met an enemy without victory or town he couldn't defeat.
我们是英国人！ 我们知道！
We're English! We know who he is!
- 你必须退出 杰夫 告诉他们  - 那当然！
- You must withdraw. Tell them,Geoff.  - Absolutely!
长枪给我
The lance.
把长枪给我
Give me the lance.
长枪拿来！
Lance!
我的老天爷啊
Oh,my giddy aunt.
这场比赛不分胜负
The match is a draw.
你疯了吗？ 你差点伤了皇室成员
You mad? You endanger a royal family member.
是他自己让自己置身危险
He endangers himself.
爵士 打得好 一如在鲁昂
Well fought,Sir Ulrich,as in Rouen.
您也是 爱德华王子
You also,Prince Edward.
你知道是我？
You knew me?
但你还是上场比赛？
And still you rode?
- 退出不是我的作风  - 我也一样
- It's not in me to withdraw.  - No. Nor me.
虽然这种事常有
Though it happens.
的确
Yes,it does.
- 祝你好运  - 您也是
- Good luck to you.  - You also.
马上长枪大赛 和锦标赛的优胜者是
The winner of the mounted joust and tournament champion
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
- 要熔要卖都随你  - 是的 大人
- Melt it,sell it,do whatever you do.  - Yes,Your Majesty.
你是冠军！
You're champion!
我还不是冠军 除非打败阿德玛 他中途退出
I'm not champion until I defeat Adhemar. He withdrew.
乌瑞克爵士
Sir Ulrich.
- 告诉我你今晚要穿什么  - 什么都不穿
- Tell me what you'll wear tonight.  - Nothing.
那么我们会引起骚动 因为我会配合你
We'll cause a sensation,for I'll dress to match.
你穿衣服穿得不烦吗？
Don't you get tired of putting on clothes?
她说的是不要穿
She's talking about taking them off.
有花没有瓣也是没有用的 不是吗？
A flower is only as good as its petals,no?
花儿一点用处也没有
A flower is good for nothing.
真的？
Really?
花儿不能吃 也不能保暖
You can't eat a flower. It doesn't keep you warm.
玫瑰也从来不曾 把男人击落马下 不是吗？
And a rose never knocked a man off a horse either,did it?
你只是个蠢女孩 不是吗？
You're just a silly girl,aren't you?
拿着花的蠢女孩 总好过骑马拿着棍棒的蠢男孩
Better a silly girl with a flower than a silly boy with a horse and stick.
再见
Goodbye.
那叫做长枪
It's called a lance.
懂不懂啊
Hello.
波尔多
- 我听到消息  - 什么？
- I have word.  - What?
阿德玛被召回自由连队
Adhemar was called back to the free companies.
是爱德华下的令 他可能整季都不会回来
Edward commanded it. He could be gone all season.
先是约瑟琳 现在又是阿德玛
First Jocelyn and now Adhemar.
说得真好
well done.
是啊 说得好
Yeah,well done.
南方前线 普瓦提耶战役
大人 比赛结果在这里
The tournament results,my lord.
乌瑞克
Ulrich.
- 杰夫  - 威廉
- Geoff.  - William.
我需要写一封信
I need to write a letter.
“亲爱的约瑟琳”不“挚爱的约瑟琳”
"Dear Jocelyn." No. "My dearest Jocelyn."
好多了
Better.
“我想你”
"I miss you."
那样不对吗？
Was that wrong?
其实要看你啦 这是你的告别式 我是说你的信
Well,it's up to you,really. It's your funeral,I mean,letter.
- 提提她的胸部  - 你想念他们
- Say something about her breasts.  - You miss them.
她的胸部？
Her breasts?
是的 你可以 但要是我 就会看她胸部以上的地方
Yes,you could,but I would tend to look above her breasts.
我想念她的喉咙？
I miss her throat?
再高一点 朝向天堂
Still higher. Towards the heavens.
月亮啊 她的双峰没那么让人印象深刻
The moon. Her breasts weren't that impressive.
月亮？ 月亮啊
The moon? The moon.
想起来实在奇怪
"It is strange to think
我已经一个月没见你了
I have not seen you in a month.
我见到了新月 却不见你
I have seen the new moon,but not you.
我看到了日升日落 却未看到你美丽的容颜
I have seen sunsets and sunrises,but nothing of your beautiful face."
非常好
That's very good.
我曾经认识一个女孩
I knew this girl once who.
她让我心碎 我说心的碎片
She broke my heart. I said the pieces- -
“我说心的碎片 小的都可以穿过针孔了”
"The pieces of my broken heart can pass through the eye of a needle. "
他写得好像我已经死了
He writes as though I had died.
是的 女士 他也像死了一样
Yes,madame. He dies as well.
她曾是约克公爵的厨子
She used to cook for the Duke of York.
我对她的思念 就像太阳对花儿的思念
I miss her like the sun misses the flower.
我对你的思念 就像太阳对花儿的思念
"I miss you like the sun misses the floWer."
就像太阳在深冬 对花儿的思念
Like the sun misses the flower in the depths of winter.
少了花儿的艳容 引导着阳光
Instead of beauty to direct its light to
心也就变得麻痹 就像你不在我身边般寒冷
the heart hardens like the frozen world your absence has sent me to.
我接下来会在巴黎出赛
I next compete in Paris.
如果你不在那里 我会觉得空虚寒冷
I'll find it empty and cold if you're not there.
我喜欢
I like it.
现在 写结语吧
And now,to finish it.
用“希望”
With "hope."
爱应该以希望作结
Love should end with hope.
我丈夫 愿他安息
My husband,God rest him
说了句我永远不会忘记的话
said something I'll never forget.
“希望引导着我”
"Hope guides me. It "
让我得以度过白日 特别是夜晚
"It gets me through the day and especially the night.
希望即使你远离我
The hope that after you leave my sight
这也不会是 我最后一次看到你
it will not be the last time I look upon you."
结语就写
Finish it With:
“献上我所有的爱威廉”
"With all the love that I possessWilliam."
你是指“乌瑞克”
You mean "Ulrich."
献上我所有的爱
"With all the love I possess
我依旧属于你
I remain yours
你芳心中的骑士
the knight of your heart."
我的主人希望你或许能够 回他几句话
My master hoped you might have something to send him in return.
巴黎
鸡鸣一次 我不会不承认他！ 鸡鸣两次 我不会！ 三次！
Cock a doodle once! I shall not deny him. Twice! I shall not. Thrice!
我不承认他
I deny him.
三次他不承认他
Thrice he denied him!
阿德玛没参加
No Adhemar.
华特
Wat.
告诉我 你见到了她吗？ 她看了信吗？
Tell me,did you see her? Did she read the letter?
是的 有的
Yes,and yes.
然后？
And?
她要来巴黎！
She's coming to Paris!
她要你带什么回来给我吗？ 一封信？ 一个信物？
Did she give you anything for me in return? A letter? A token?
她要给我一个信物？ 她有
Did she give me a token? She did.
我是说 嗯
Uh,I mean,um.
是什么？ 快给我
Well,what is it? Give it to me.
好耶！
Yes!
太好了！
Hell,yes!
她… 因为她… 那表示她… 太好了！
She-- Because she's-- That means she-- Yeah!
五十
Cinquante.
那是个不错的整数
That's a nice round number.
借过
Excuse- moi.
他们赌法国人 而非乌瑞克爵士会赢得比赛
They wager that a Frenchman,not Sir Ulrich,will win the tournament.
但赌注是五十个银币
But the amount is 50 florins.
- 那是我们全部的钱  - 就是要赌我们所有的钱
- That's all we got.  - If we had 60,it would be that.
乌瑞克对抗这里每个法国人？
Ulrich against every Frenchman here?
他已经连续赢得四场比赛 而且阿德玛不在这里
He's won four tournaments in a row. And Adhemar isn't here.
我也查过盾牌了 约翰波蒙在这里
I check shields too. John Beaumont's here.
席德伯爵 勃艮地的菲力浦 都是法国的冠军
Count Theobald,Philip of Burgundy all French champions.
英国人无法赢得
Englishmen will not win
这场法国锦标赛
this French tournament.
英国人的脚 在法国土地上站不稳
English legs are unsteady on French soil.
闭上你的嘴 可以吗？
Shut your mouth,all right?!
洛伦 赌吧 胜算很大 赢了我就可以买间酒馆
Come on,Roland. It's a good bet. Win and I can buy my own tavern.
- 我就可以专职写作 - 我可以买个炼炉
- I could write full- time.  - A forge for me.
而且法国酒 对英国人的胃来说也太烈了
And because French wine is too much for English bellies.
听着 老兄 我就快揍人了 我对上帝发誓 真的！
Listen,I'm about this fonging close,mate. I swear to God,Quasimodo!
我只想回家 而且我的钱 够我回家一百次了
All I want is to go home,and I've enough for that trip a hundred times.
最重要的是 连教宗都是法国人！
And most importantly,because the pope himself is French!
教宗或许是法国人 但耶稣是英国人 赌了
The pope may be French,but Jesus is English. You're on.
有公主来看他 他不会输的
He won't lose with the princess watching him.
他金发碧眼！ 他极度恼火！
He's blond! He's pissed!
他会上场的！ 利顿斯坦！ 利顿斯坦！
He'll see you in the lists! Lichtenstein! Lichtenstein!
他金发碧眼！ 他黝黑健壮！ 他来自盖德兰！
He's blond! He's tan! He comes from Gelderland!
他来自盖德兰！
He comes from Gelderland!
盖德兰！
Gelderland!
- 你想他会来吗？  - 就像太阳会升起一样肯定
- You think he will come?  - As sure as the sun will rise.
你喜欢大教堂
You favor cathedrals.
我是来忏悔的
I come for confession.
还有来欣赏玻璃
And the glass.
一个沉闷灰暗世界里的 缤纷色彩
A riot of color in a dreary,gray world.
你不认为吗？
Don't you think?
真美
It's beautiful.
你送来的信 也让我有同样的感觉
I feel the same about the letter you sent.
跟我说话
Speak to me.
说说那些话
Speak those words.
我会为你赢得这场锦标赛
I will win this tournament for you.
什么？
Excuse me?
我会为你赢得这场锦标赛 我会为你打败每一个骑士
I'll win this tournament in your name. I'll defeat each knight for you.
你的美会反映在我手臂的力量 和我马儿的侧腹上
Your beauty will be reflected in the power of my arm and my horse's flanks.
哇
Wow.
真的？
Really?
真的？ 它的侧腹？
Really? Its flanks?
乌瑞克 我想听的是诗句
I wish to hear poetry,Ulrich.
我还没准备好
Well,I'm not ready.
我准备好了 为什么女人 事事必须照男人的时间表来？
I am. Why must everything for a woman be run on a man's schedule?
男人要做的事比较多 而且
Well,a man's day is fuller,and
他的时间也比较宝贵
he has more demands on his time.
- 是吗？  - 是的
- Is that so?  - Yes.
或许吧
Maybe.
不是吗？
No?
我要听诗句
I demand poetry
我要听 而且现在就要听
and when I want it. And I want it now.
你的双峰
Your breasts
在你的喉咙下方
they're below your throat.
约瑟琳 我要怎么做才能证明 我对你的爱？ 怎么做？
Jocelyn,how may I prove my love to you? How?
- 你是认真在问？  - 是的
- Do you ask in earnest?  - Yes.
如果你要证明你的爱
If you would prove your love
- 就做出你最差的表现  - 最差的表现？
- do your worst.  - My worst?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
不要用你高度的名望 为我赢得大赛
Instead of winning to honor me with your high reputation
而是一反常态 表现走样
act against your character and do badly.
- 表现走样？  - 输掉比赛
- Do badly?  - Lose.
输掉只会证明我是窝囊废
Losing proves that I'm a loser.
错 输了更能证明你的爱
Wrong. Losing is a much keener test of your love.
输会跟你的自怜相抵触
Losing would contradict your self- love.
会显示你对爱人 而非对自己的顺从！
It would show obedience to your lover and not yourself!
- 真的？  - 女人 安静！
- Really?  - Woman,shh!
别叫我安静 而不骂他！ 你走！ 走啊！
Do not "shh" me and spare him! Now be gone! Go!
你的答案是什么？
What is your answer?
我不会输的
I will not lose.
那么你就不爱我
Then you do not love me.
意大利贞节的保护者
The Protector of Italian Virginity
让法国群情激动的骑士
the Lance that thrilled France
男人中的男人！
the Harasser of Paraser!
在拉罗谢尔打败群敌！
He gave them hell at La Rochelle!
上帝旨意的执行者！
The Enforcer of our Lord God!
独一无二的
The one,the only
乌瑞克
Sir Ulrich
冯利顿斯坦爵士！
von Lichtenstein!
天啊 我真行！
God,I'm good!
他马儿的侧腹
His horse's flanks.
也许在他家乡 那代表了爱
Maybe where he comes from,it means love.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
- 输掉比赛  - 我不懂
- Losing.  - I don't understand.
我也不懂
I don't understand.too
他爱我
He loves me.
你瞎了吗？
Are you blind?
- 你有看到旗子吗？  - 我看到了 可以吗？
- Did you see the flag?  - I saw it,okay?
我知道
I know.
你故意先落后 再来个戏剧性的胜利
You're dropping behind for a more dramatic victory.
约瑟琳要我输掉比赛 来证明我的爱
Look,Jocelyn told me to lose to prove my love.
- 我宁可你是瞎掉  - 威廉 你别傻了
- I'd rather you were blind.  - Don't be foolish,Will.
- 女人不过都想要证明罢了  - 证明什么？
- Each woman wants proof,that's all.  - Proof of what?
她的腿不是平白无故地分开
Her legs weren't uncrossed for nothing.
- 我没有分开她的腿  - 那我们干嘛这么做？
- I haven't uncrossed her legs.  - Then why are we doing this?!
就是因为！
Because!
因为
Because
我爱她
I love her.
- 我会输光光！  - 所以才叫赌博嘛
- I'm going to lose everything!  - That's why it's called gambling.
痛吧！ 痛死你！
Pain! Here's your pain!
但是非常罗曼蒂克
It's very romantic,though.
你到底是女人还是铁匠？
Are you a woman or a blacksmith?
有时候我两者都是
Sometimes I'm both.
好痛啊！ 可恶！
Ooh,that chafes!
把他放下啦
Put him down.
没有骑士会故意输掉
No knight has distanced himself with victories.
如果你剩下的几场比赛都赢 而且你的对手都大败特败
If you win your remaining matches and your opponents take key losses
你就可以进入准决赛 或者决赛
you could make the semis,or the finals.
- 至少盔甲证明了它的能耐  - 那你的爱呢？
- At least the armor's proven itself. - And your love?
你证明你的爱了吗？
Have you proven that?
华特 想想小时候对教堂的感觉 那份戒慎恐惧 那份热情
Wat,you remember church as a boy. The fear,the passion.
那就是我对她的感觉
That's what she makes me feel.
因为如此 我的玫瑰经 只为约瑟琳一个人念
And for that,I say my rosary to Jocelyn and no one else.
威廉 那样说很不敬
William,that's blasphemous.
那就让我在地狱受苦吧
Then may I burn in hell.
退出比赛
Withdraw.
就这么输了算了 不要再撑下去了
Lose that way. Take no more punishment.
洛伦
Oh,Roland.
我家小姐要我来传话 如果你爱她
My lady sends this message. If you love her- -
我知道 我知道 我必须输 她没在看吗？
I know,I know. I must lose. Isn't she watching?
她说你若爱她 就不会再输了
She says if you love her,you won't lose again.
她说你若爱她 就会赢得这场大赛
She says if you love her,you will win this tournament.
她在那里 爱的化身 你的维纳斯
There she is,the embodiment of love. Your Venus.
我真恨她
And how I hate her.
- 我真不懂女人  - 我也不懂 但她们很懂我们
- I don't understand women.  - Nor do I,but they understand us.
也许不包括你
Maybe not you.
好耶！
Yes!
女人哪
Women,eh?
四十八
Forty eight
四十九
forty nine
五十
and fifty.
谢谢各位了 很高兴跟你们做生意
Thank you,gentlemen. A pleasure doing business with you.
到伦敦记得来找我们 也许在世界冠军赛时
Look us up if you're in London,the world championships,maybe.
别那么沮丧嘛 拿去 我请你们喝一杯
Don't look too sad. Here,have a drink on me.
他身手敏捷 他幽默风趣 他还很会赚钱 利顿斯坦！
He's quick,he's funny and makes lots of money,Lichtenstein!
格温娜维尔走向蓝斯洛
Guinevere comes to Lancelot.
小姐 好好服侍他睡
Bed him well,my lady.
好好服侍他
Bed him well.
我们在庆祝会上很想你
We missed you at banquet.
“我们”？
"We"?
我
I.
约瑟琳
Jocelyn.
你的奖赏
Your prize.
我的奖赏
My prize.
我不配得奖
I am not worthy of a prize.
那么谁有资格？
Then who is?
我的女仆告诉我 有时候你的属下
My maid tells me that sometimes your varlets
叫你威廉
call you William.
是不是 乌瑞克爵士？
Is this so,Sir Ulrich?
是的
Yes.
的确如此
It is so.
你叫什么名字对我不重要
Your name makes no matter to me.
只要你是我的
Just so I can call you my own.
但约瑟琳 我的确是你的呀
But Jocelyn,I am your own.
该死
Damn,girl.
你需要看医生
You need a surgeon.
他来过了 他说我死不了 虽然不觉的这样
He's been. He says I will live,though it doesn't feel that way.
威廉 这疼痛都是我害的
Oh,William. This pain is my doing.
的确是
Yes,it is.
尽管
Although
我父亲
my father
教我要把苦果
taught me to take the bad
当良药吃
with the good.
你所说的良药
This good you speak of.
也同样会来自于我
It will be my doing as well.
你们上次回来是何时？ 我只离开了六个月
How long since any of you have been back? I've only been gone 6 months.
我两年
Two years for me.
我三年
Three years.
五年 漫长的五年
Five. Five long years.
威廉？
William?
十二
Twelve.
十二年
Twelve years.
他要去当学徒？
He's to be an apprentice?
多久？
How long for?
七年
Seven years.
艾克特爵士？
Sir Ector?
我就是在伦敦赛场外 跟您说过话的补屋顶工匠
I'm the thatcher. I spoke to you outside London Stadium.
是的 我记得
Oh,yes. I remember.
就是这男孩？
Is this the boy?
孩子 过来让我看看
Step forward,son. Let me look at you.
洛伦 小心点！
Careful with that,Roland!
孩子 你怕我吗？
Are you afraid of me,boy?
你的牙齿长齐了吗？
Have you got most of your teeth?
让我看看你的手臂够壮吗？
Show me your arm. Is it strong?
他饿得瘦巴巴的
Well,he's a half- starved little scarecrow.
但他很有个性
But he has spirit.
我可以领你见识一个广阔 充满冒险的世界
I can show you a great wide world full of adventure
还有你不曾梦想过的 奇人异事
and marvels you do not yet dream of.
可以帮我把东西装上马吗？
Can you pack my horse and lead it?
去吧 跟你父亲道别
Well,come on. Say goodbye to your father.
威廉 他是真正的骑士 尽你所能的观察和学习
He's a real knight,William. Watch and learn all you can.
我只能为你做到这样了
It's all I can do for you,son.
去改变你的命运 过比我好的生活
Now go change your stars and live a better life than I have.
洛伦 告诉这孩子该做些什么
Roland,show the boy his duties.
- 父亲？ 我怕  - 怕什么？
- Father? I'm afraid.  - Of what?
我会不知道回家的路
I won't know the way home.
别傻了 威廉 跟随你的脚步就行了
Don't be foolish,William. You just follow your feet.
伦敦
London.
世界冠军赛
# 猜猜今天谁回来了？ #
# Guess who just got back today? #
# 已经离开的那些狂野的男孩子们 #
# Them wild-eyed boys that had been away #
# 没有变化，没有什么太多要说的 #
# Haven't changed,haven't much to say #
# 但是男子汉，我依然觉得爵士迷们很疯狂 #
# But man,I still think them cats are crazy #
# 他们会问你你是否在周围 #
# They were asking if you were around #
# 你过的怎么样，你在哪里被发现的 #
# How you was,where you could be found #
# 告诉他们你住在市中心 #
# Told them you were living downtown #
# 让所有的老男人们都很疯狂 #
# Driving all the old men crazy #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
# The boys are back in town #
为我们欢呼吧 伦敦！
Give us a shout out,London!
# 我说 #
# I said #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
# The boys are back in town #
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
# 把这件事传的沸沸扬扬 #
# Spread the word around #
# 猜猜谁回到镇上了 #
# Guess who's back in town #
# 星期五晚上他们打扮的很时尚 #
# Friday night they'll be dressed to kill #
# 在恐龙酒吧里烧烤 #
# Down at Dino's bar and grill #
# 酒会流出，血会溢出 #
# The drink will flow and blood will spill #
# 如果男孩子想打架，你最好让他们做 #
# And if the boys want to fight,you'd better let them #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
# The boys are back in town #
- 阿德玛在这里 他报名了  - 一定是打仗打烦了
- Adhemar's here. He's entered.  - Must have grown bored with war.
不 是黑王子下的令 他必须解散他的军队
No,the Black Prince commanded it. He had to disband his army.
他们每到一个地方 尽会闹事掠夺
They were reveling,pillaging town after town.
抢劫、杀人、洗劫教堂
Robbing,murdering,ransacking churches.
用最新的方法 犯下最古老的罪
Committing the oldest sins in the newest ways.
我们终将再遭遇 乌瑞克爵士
At last we will face each other again,Sir Ulrich.
在这世界冠军赛
And at the World Championship.
正如我跟你保证过的
And as I promised you before
你会躺在地上仰望着我
you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
忘掉过去吧
Let the past die.
据说我不在时 你表现极佳 无论在场内或场外
You've done well in my absence,on the field and off,I'm told.
赢得奖品、马匹、女人
Winning trophies,horses,women.
你都是这样排顺序的？
You put them in that order?
通常是 但有一些例外
Generally,with a few exceptions.
她很美吧？
Beautiful,isn't she?
一项品质精纯的奖品 你不觉得吗？
A real thoroughbred trophy,don't you think?
- 你说得好像她是箭靶  - 不是吗？
- You speak of her like a target.  - Isn't she?
不
No.
她是箭
She is the arrow.
我已经跟她父亲展开商议了
I've begun negotiations with her father.
我要她当我的新娘
I'm to make her my bride.
她会被上好鞍
She'll be saddled
摆设在我的火炉顶上
and placed on my mantle.
是箭靶或箭并不重要
Target or arrow,it doesn't matter.
我将会拥有她
I will have her.
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
- 你会怎么击倒他？  - 用棍子 趁他熟睡时
- How would you beat him?  - With a sticK,while he slept.
但在马上呢？ 用长枪呢？
But on a horse? With a lance?
那个人所向无敌
That man is unbeatable.
你好
Hello there.
- 你是乌瑞克爵士  - 是的
- You're Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.  - Yes.
你是我最喜欢的骑士 我们比长枪时 我都说我是你
You're my favorite knight. When we joust,I always say I'm you.
你怎么会来奇普塞？ 今天没有游行啊
What are you doing in Cheapside? There's no parade today.
你可以保守秘密吗？
Can you keep a secret?
我在奇普塞出生 就在那边的转角
I was born in Cheapside,just around the corner there.
- 真的吗 爵爷？  - 真的
- Truly,Sir Ulrich?  - Truly.
我就住在那里
I only live just there.
你几岁了？
How old are you?
- 九岁半  - 九岁半啊
- Nine and one half.  - Nine and one half.
不知道你是否记得一个人 虽然他可能早就死了
I wonder if you remember a man,though he may have died long ago.
他长得跟骑士一样高大 名字叫约翰柴契尔
He was as tall as a knight. His name was John Thatcher.
- 我当然记得他  - 真的？
- Of course I remember him.  - You do?
是啊 他还住在那里
Yes. He lives there still.
有时候我们会看到他坐在窗边 但没有人知道为什么
Sometimes we see him sitting at the window,but no one knows why.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他是瞎子 爵爷
He's blind,sir.
有人来了吗？
Is someone there?
如果你是来拿渔网的 我还没修补好 明天再来吧
If you're here for the net,I'm not done yet. Come tomorrow.
你是谁？
Who are you?
一个骑士
A knight.
我名叫乌瑞克
My nameis Ulrich.
乌瑞克？ 我听过人们 在赛场上高叫这个名字
Ulrich? I hear that name being chanted from the stadium.
有何贵干？
What business have you here?
我有消息 补屋顶师傅
I have word,Master Thatcher.
令公子的消息
Word of your son.
我的威廉？ 爵爷 快请进
Of my William? Well,come in,sir.
什么消息？ 他活着吗？
What word? Does he live?
是的 他活着
Aye. He lives.
他很好
He is very well.
他希望你知道
He wanted you to know
他终究改变了他的命运
that he changed his stars after all.
他跟随了他的脚步吗？
And has he followed his feet?
他终于找到回家的路了吗？
Has he found his way home at last?
是的
Yes.
父亲
Father.
威廉 我的孩子
Oh,William. Oh,my boy.
我真想见见这个华特 还有洛伦
I should like to meet this Wat. And Roland too.
你会见到的
You will,Father.
女人呢？ 你有特定对像 还是很多个？
And what of women? Is there a certain one or many?
我有一个心仪的对象
There is a certain one.
我也想见见她
I should like to meet her too.
漏水成这样不行
This leak won't do,Father.
- 尤其在补屋顶工匠家中  - 这对瞎眼人来说不成问题
- Not in a thatcher's chamber.  - It's quite fitting for a blind one.
我是补屋顶的
Well,a thatcher I am.
我会帮你修好
I'll fix it.
活着 我以为他死了 我真是疯了
Alive. I thought he was dead,which is mad
因为他仍那么强壮 非常强壮
because he was also so strong. Very strong.
- 杰夫  - 约瑟琳
- Geoff.  - Jocelyn.
今天真是愈来愈精采
This day just gets better and better.
有人死了吗？
Somebody die?
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
阿德玛
Adhemar
昨晚跟踪你到奇普塞
followed you last night. To Cheapside.
他看到你父亲
He saw your father.
威廉 他们跟我要你的证明书
Will,they asked me for your patents.
他们在场上等着逮捕你
They're waiting for you in the lists to arrest you.
十二个皇家侍卫
A dozen royal guards.
- 他们会把你抓上示众台  - 但我马上就要跟阿德玛交手
- They'll put you in the stocks.  - But I face Adhemar in five minutes.
不 你丧失了比赛权 他们已经记下了
No,you forfeit. They've already marked it down.
把马上鞍 他们可以逮捕你的行李而非你
Saddle the horses. They can arrest your baggage,not you.
站住
Halt.
你有何感想
So,what do you think
既然你知道了我是谁？
now that you know what I am?
威廉 要知道你是谁 必须花上一辈子的时间
To know what you are,William,would take a lifetime.
我很愿意这么做 但你现在必须快点跑
One I am willing to give. But now you must run.
快跑吧 我会跟你一起跑
Run,and I will run with you.
约瑟琳 我不能跑
Jocelyn,I cannot run.
我是个骑士 我要排除万难！
I am a knight,and I will put myself to the hazard!
在你心中 不是在文件上 而他们在乎的只有文件！
In your heart,not on paper. And paper's what matters to them!
威廉 我爱你
William,I love you.
我爱你 只有你
I love you. You.
- 我不要看你上示众台  - 但要看我逃跑？ 不！
- I won't see you led to the stocks.  - But you'll see me run? No!
去你的自尊 威廉
Damn your pride,William.
是你不愿意见到自己逃跑
It is only you that will not see you run.
自尊是他们夺不走的！
Pride's the one thing they can't take!
但他们可以践踏你的自尊 他们可以 也会这么做
But they can take it from you. They can and they will.
他们绝对会这么做
Oh,they will.
但他们夺不走爱
But love they cannot take.
那我们要住在哪里？
And where will we live?
我的破房子吗？
In my hovel?
- 在冬天里跟猪共处一室？  - 是的 跟猪共处一室
- With the pigs inside in winter?  - Yes,William,with the pigs.
跟猪共处一室
With the pigs.
穷人可以为爱结婚
The poor can marry for love.
约瑟琳 你不懂！
Jocelyn,you speak of what you do not know!
威廉 我求你
William,I beg you.
求求你
Please.
跑吧 为了爱
Run. Do it for love.
洛伦 你要我跑吗？
Roland,you would see me run?
你呢 杰夫？
And you,Geoff?
我也希望你这么做 衷心这么希望
I wish it too,with all the pieces of my heart.
华特？ 你跟我？ 我们不轻易逃跑的
Wat? You and l? We aren't runners.
跑吧
Yes.
威廉 今天我们得跑
William,today we are.
威廉 跑吧
Run,William.
我不会逃的！
I will not run!
我是个骑士
I am a knight.
各位
Well,boys
好事终难长久
all good things must come to an end.
我们就一起做个结束吧
Let's end them together.
你自愿退出吧
You will remove yourself from this position of honor.
我是来参赛的
I am here to compete.
你是来被逮捕就范的
You are here to be arrested.
好！
All right!
一心想摘星的人
He that strives to touch a star
往往会失足于
oft stumbles
一个枝微末节
at a simple straw.
你打也打了
You have been weighed.
比也比了
You have been measured.
而且发现你能力不足
And you have been found wanting.
世事古难全啊威廉
It's one loss or anotherWilliam.
你在哪方面能击败我？
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
洛伦 你走吧
Leave,Roland.
随他们高兴吧
Let them have me.
威廉 上帝爱你
God love you,William.
我也是
So do l.
走！ 快走开！
Go! Disperse!
不然我要你们好看！
Or I will fong you!
我以拿撒勒的耶稣基督
As Jesus Christ the Nazarene and his holy mother
和圣母玛丽亚做我的见证 我会要你们好看！
the Virgin Mary are my witnesses,I will fong you!
我会揍扁你们！ 痛死你们！
I will rip you! Fist! Pain!
我会打烂你们！ 要你们痛苦！ 非常痛苦！
I'll stick my fist and break you! Pain! Lots of pain!
我们麻烦大了
We're in trouble.
听我说
Listen to me.
我们真是哥俩好
What a pair we make,huh?
都试着隐藏真实身份
Both trying to hide who we are.
却也都失败了
Both unable to do so.
你的同伴爱你
Your men love you.
即使我不了解你 知道这点也就够了
If I knew nothing else about you,that would be enough.
但你在你应该退出的时候 勇敢不屈
But you also tilt when you should withdraw.
那也是骑士精神
That is knightly too.
放了他
Release him.
他或许看来出身低微
He may appear to be of humble origins
但我私人的史学家发现
but my personal historians have discovered
他的远祖是皇室成员
that he descends from an ancient royal line.
这是我说的
This is my word.
因此 你们不得争辩
And as such,is beyond contestation.
现在
Now
让我回报 你曾经对我展露的情谊
if I may repay the kindness you once showed me.
屈膝跪下吧
Take a knee.
谨以我父王爱德华国王 赋予我的权力
By the power vested in me by my father,King Edward
并在这里所有人的见证下
and by all the witnesses here
我封你为
I dub thee
威廉爵士
Sir William.
起身吧威廉爵士
AriseSir William.
你能上场吗？
Can you joust?
我还有比赛要完成呢
There's my tournament to finish.
你可以上场比赛 或者还是要弃权？
Now,are you fit to compete,or shall the forfeit stand?
我没问题
I'm fit.
我会找人通知你的对手 去场上找他的盾牌吧
I shall have your opponent informed. Look for his shield on the lists.
马上去
At once.
谢谢你 殿下
Thank you,my lord.
爱德华王子万岁！
All hail Prince Edward!
各位大人、女士
My lords,my ladies
和其他人民
and all you other people.
请欢迎菲利浦德维崔之子 吉列之孙
I give you the son of Philippe de Vitry,son of Gilles.
- 你确定吗？  - 确定
- Are you sure?  - Yes.
这不过是漆了黑漆的糖衣
It's nothing but spun sugar and boot black.
目标虽然小
It's a small target
瞄准他的心脏
but aim for his heart.
功勋彪炳
doer of daring deeds
所向披靡的伯爵
conqueror of countless kingdoms,Count
阿德玛！
Adhemar!
天啊 我去找医生
Oh,God. I'll get the surgeon.
洛伦！
Roland!
你就是医生
You're the surgeon.
快点
Come on.
他装了尖头
He tipped it.
凯蒂 快领我回起点
Kate,get me back to one.
否则我们就得弃权
Otherwise we forfeit.
那个黑心的浑蛋！
Dirty son of a bitch!
凯蒂 我没办法呼吸
Kate,I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
正如我说的 补屋顶工匠
As I said,thatcher.
你在哪方面能击败我？
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
那方面是不存在的
Such a place does not exist.
她来了
She's here.
和你的父亲一起来了
With your father.
改变命运
Change your stars.
你我好好比一场吧
Let's dance,you and l.
目前是二比零
It's two lances to none.
你得让他落马或杀了他 才能获胜
You must unhorse him or kill him. It's the only way to win.
- 你需要多加些衬垫  - 不了 我不穿了
- You need more padding.  - No,leave it off.
穿着我会无法呼吸
I can't breathe with it on.
长枪给我
Lance.
我抓都抓不稳
I can barely grip it.
可恶
Damn.
把枪绑在我手臂上
Lash it to my arm.
华特
Wat
把枪绑在我手臂上
Iash it to me arm.
照他说的做
Do it.
各位！
Good people!
我忘了说介绍词！
I missed my introduction!
但请你们
But please
请你们 请求你们
please,I pray you.
现在好好倾听
Hear it now.
因为我接下来
For I would lay rest
放下花言巧语
the grace in my tongue
只说简单的
and speak plain.
像今天这种罕见的机会
Days like these
不该让拙劣的言词 贬损了它的价值
are far too rare to cheapen with heavy- handed words.
因此 我想 我就不再无事自扰
And so,I'm afraid,without any ado whatsoever
大人 抱歉
Excuse me,my lord.
他就在那里！ 你们的同胞！
Here he is! One of your own!
在这个场上诞生的璞石
Born a stone's throw from this very stadium
现在就在你们的面前
and here before you now.
约翰柴契尔之子
The son of John Thatcher
威廉柴契尔爵士！
Sir William Thatcher!
那是你的名字
That's your name.
威廉柴契尔爵士
Sir William Thatcher.
你父亲听到了
Your father heard that.
威廉 祝你成功
Godspeed,William.
威廉！
William!
你打也打了
You have been weighed.
比也比了
You've been measured.
而且绝对的
And you absolutely
能力不足
have been found wanting.
欢迎来到新世界
Welcome to the new world.
愿上帝保全你 如果他这么做是对的
God save you,if it is right that he should do so.
威廉！
William!
太好了！
Yes!
他赢了！ 他赢了！
He's won! He's won!
威廉 你打败了他！
You beat him,Will!
威廉
Oh,William.
我要写下这个故事
I'm going to write this story.
王子和骑士的故事？
About the prince and the knights?
不 全部 一个艺术家要写尽人事
No,all of it. All human activity lies within the artist's scope.
你的就免了
Maybe not yours.
# 她其实就是一台高速运转的机器 #
# She was a fast machine,#
# 只不过让自己的发动机永葆清洁 #
# She kept her motor clean,#
# 她也许是我见过最好的女人 #
# She was the best damn woman that I ever seen,#
# 因为她有一双不明晰的眼睛  #
# She had sightless eyes,#
# 而且她从不撒谎 #
# Telling me no lies,#
# 用那美国式的胴体诱惑把我制服 #
# Knocking me out with those American thighs,#
# 我试图索取更多 #
# Taking more than her share,#
# 结果我却不堪重负 #
# Had me fighting for air,#
# 她说来吧 事实上我已经在那了 #
# She told me to come,but I was already there,#
# 然后墙就开始抖动 #
# Cause the walls started shaking,#
# 大地也在晃动 #
# The earth was quaking,#
# 我的思想已经极度疼痛 #
# My mind was aching,#
# 你知道我们在干什么 因为你 #
# And we were making it and you #
# 整晚的折磨我 #
# Shook me all night long,#
# All night long #
# 我已付出了代价 #
# I've paid my dues #
# 一次又一次 #
# Time after time #
# 我服了刑 #
# I've done my sentence #
# 但没有犯罪 #
# But committed no crime #
# 我犯过了一些 #
# And bad mistakes #
# 严重的错误 #
# I've made a few #
# 我自作自受 #
# I've had my share of sand,kicked in my face #
# 但我都熬过来了 #
# But I've come through #
# 我要继续 #
# And I need to go on and on and on and on #
# 我们是冠军 我的朋友们 #
# We are the champions,my friends #
# 我们会一直战斗到最后 #
# And we'll keep on fighting till the end #
# 我们是冠军 #
# We are the champions #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# No time for losers #
# 因为我们是世界冠军 #
# 'Cause we are the champions of the world #
# 我鞠躬谢幕 #
# I've taken my bows #
# 将落下帷幕 #
# And my curtain calls #
# 你们给我带来名誉和财富 #
# You've bought me fame and fortune #
# 和随之而来的一切 #
# And everything that goes with it #
# 我感谢你们 #
# I thank you all #
# 但没有任何游乐 #
# But it's been no bed of roses there #
# 也不是欢乐的海洋 #
# No pleasure cruise #
# 我认为这是一个摆在全人类面前的挑战 #
# I consider it a challenge before the whole human race #
# 而我绝不会输 #
# And I ain't gonna lose #
# 我要继续 #
# And I need to go on and on and on and on #
# 我们是冠军 我的朋友们 #
# We are the champions,my friends #
# 我们会一直战斗到最后 #
# And we'll keep on fighting till the end #
# 我们是冠军 #
# We are the champions #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# No time for losers #
# 因为我们是世界冠军 #
# 'Cause we are the champions #
# 我们是冠军 #
# We are the champions #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# No time for losers #
# 因为我们是冠军 #
# 'Cause we are the champions #
你输了
Your round.